<pool id="survey_design_critiq_validity_pool">
    <title>stat_sampling_ckpt_survey_design_critiq_validity_pool</title>
    <multiple_choice id="q1_survey_design_critiq_validity">
        <!-- LO: survey_design_critiq_validity -->
        <body>
            <p>When conducting a survey, which of the following is the most important reason to use a <em style="italic">random</em> sample?</p>
        </body>
        <input shuffle="true">
            <choice value="A">To get a significant result</choice>
            <choice value="B">To avoid bias and to get a representative sample</choice>
            <choice value="C">So that we can make causal conclusions</choice>
            <choice value="D">To ensure truthful answers to the survey&#x27;s questions</choice>
        </input>
        <part>
            <response match="A" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. A random sample does not guarantee a <em style="italic"
                        >significant</em> result, it guarantees a <em style="italic"
                        >representative</em> result. Although randomness is a necessary ingredient
                    of any study that produces significant results, that is not the <em
                        style="italic">most important</em> reason for random selection.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B" score="10">
                <feedback>Correct. <em style="italic">Random selection</em> ensures that the sample is <em style="italic">unbiased</em> on average, so that the results of the study
                    can be generalized to the population.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="C" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Random <em style="italic">selection</em> isn&#x27;t what allows us
                    to determine causation; that would be ensured only by random <em style="italic"
                        >assignment</em> to treatments.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="D" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. The truthfulness of the subjects is not affected one way or the
                    other by the way the subjects were selected.</feedback>
            </response>
        </part>
    </multiple_choice>
  
  <multiple_choice id="q2_survey_design_critiq_validity">
        <!-- LO: survey_design_critiq_validity -->
        <body>
            <p>When conducting a survey, which of the following is the <em style="bold">most
                    important</em> reason to avoid using a <em style="italic">volunteer</em>
                sample?</p>
        </body>
        <input shuffle="true">
            <choice value="A">You might not get a significant result.</choice>
            <choice value="B">To ensure truthful answers to the survey&#x27;s questions.</choice>
            <choice value="C">Your conclusions could not be reliably generalized to a larger
                population.</choice>
            <choice value="D">In order to get stronger opinions expressed.</choice>
        </input>
        <part>
            <response match="A" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Volunteer samples tend to contain people with a strong enough
                    opinion on the topic to call or write in. Strong opinions in on both sides of
                    the issue may give very significant results. However, these strong opinions may
                    be strongly biased.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. There is no reason to assume that volunteer samples give
                    answers that are more or less truthful than any other method.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="C" score="10">
                <feedback>Correct. The point of sampling is to be able to generalize about a larger
                    population and volunteer samples do not represent the population as a whole
                    since they tend to contain people with a strong enough opinion on the topic to
                    call or write in and therefore are a biased sample.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="D" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Volunteer samples tend to contain responses from individuals
                    who care the most about an issue and therefore have the strongest
                    opinions.</feedback>
            </response>
        </part>
    </multiple_choice>
</pool>
