<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pool id="id_study_design_pool">
    <title>stat_design_studies_ckpt1_id_study_design_pool</title>
    <multiple_choice id="q1_id_study_design" select="multiple">
        <!-- LO:  -->
        <body>
            <p>Which of the following is an extremely important design element to have in an
                experimental study? Check all that apply. </p>
        </body>
        <input shuffle="false">
            <choice value="A">Treatments that are imposed by the experimenter</choice>
            <choice value="B">A placebo</choice>
            <choice value="C">Groups which are exactly the same size</choice>
            <choice value="D">Randomized selection of participants</choice>
        </input>
        <part>
            <response match="A" score="8">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While it is true that assignment of treatment by experimenters
                    is a key aspect of experimental studies there is at least one other important
                    design element that you are missing. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While placebos may be useful (or even essential) in some
                    studies they may be unethical in others. Also, there is at least one correct
                    design element. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="C" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While it is nice to have groups of approximately the same size,
                    it is not important that the sizes be identical or even necessarily that close.
                    Also, there is at least one correct design element. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="D" score="8">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While random selection of participants is a very important
                    aspect of experimental design there is at least one other important design
                    element that you are missing. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="A,B" score="5">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While it is true that assignment of treatment by experimenters
                    is a key aspect of experimental studies, placebos are not required (and may be
                    unethical in some studies) and there is at least one other important design
                    element that you are missing. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="A,C" score="5">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While it is true that assignment of treatment by experimenters
                    is a key aspect of experimental studies, it is not essential that groups be of
                    identical size. Also, there is at least one other important design element that
                    you are missing. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="A,D" score="10">
                <feedback>Correct. Randomly assigning subjects to treatments administered by
                    researchers are two very important aspects to good experimental design.
                </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B,C" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Placebos are not required (and may even be unethical in some
                    studies) and it is not essential that groups be of identical size. Also, there
                    is at least one correct design element. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B,D" score="5">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While random selection of participants is a very important
                    aspect of experimental design, placebos are not required (and may even be
                    unethical in some studies) and there is at least one other important design
                    element that you are missing. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="C,D" score="5">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While random selection of participants is a very important
                    aspect of experimental design, it is not essential that groups be of identical
                    size and there is at least one other important design element that you are
                    missing. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="A,B,C" score="3">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While it is true that assignment of treatment by experimenters
                    is a key aspect of experimental studies, placebos are not required (and may even
                    be unethical in some studies) and it is not essential that groups be of
                    identical size. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="A,B,D" score="8">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While it is true that assignment of treatment by experimenters
                    is a key aspect of experimental studies and random selection of participants is
                    a very important aspect of experimental design, placebos are not required (and
                    may even be unethical in some studies). </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="A,C,D" score="8">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While it is true that assignment of treatment by experimenters
                    is a key aspect of experimental studies and random selection of participants is
                    a very important aspect of experimental design, it is not essential that groups
                    be of identical size. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B,C,D" score="3">
                <feedback>Incorrect. While random selection of participants is a very important
                    aspect of experimental design, placebos are not required (and may even be
                    unethical in some studies) and it is not essential that groups be of identical
                    size. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="A,B,C,D" score="5">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Placebos are not required (and may even be unethical in some
                    studies) and it is not essential that groups be of identical size. </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="*" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. There are important aspects of experimental design you are
                    missing. </feedback>
            </response>
        </part>
    </multiple_choice>


    <multiple_choice id="q4_id_study_design" select="single">
        <body>In an experiment to see if aspirin reduces the chance of having a heart attack, which of the following would be a placebo?</body>
        <input labels="false" shuffle="true">
            <choice value="A">The place where the subjects go when they have a heart
                attack</choice>
            <choice value="B">A dummy pill that looks like aspirin but has no active
                ingredients</choice>
            <choice value="C">A procedure for deciding who gets the aspirin treatment</choice>
            <choice value="D">The sampling method</choice>
            <choice value="E">The randomization procedure</choice>
        </input>
        <part>
            <response match="A" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. The word <em style="italic">placebo</em> doesn&#x27;t refer to a place.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B" score="10">
                <feedback>Correct. A placebo is a nonactive treatment used in a study for proper
                    comparison. In this case, it ensures that any comparative effect in the aspirin
                    group is really due to the active ingredient rather than just due to the
                    "placebo effect." </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="C" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. A <em style="italic">placebo</em> isn&#x27;t a procedure, and it doesn&#x27;t determine who
                    gets the treatment.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="D" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. A <em style="italic">placebo</em> isn&#x27;t a sampling method.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="E" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. A <em style="italic">placebo</em> isn&#x27;t a procedure, and it doesn&#x27;t cause
                    randomization.</feedback>
            </response>
        </part>
    </multiple_choice>


    <multiple_choice id="q5_id_study_design" select="single">
        <body>
            <p>Students in a large statistics class were randomly divided into two groups. The first group took the midterm exam with soft music playing in the background, and the second group took the exam with no music playing. After the exam was completed, a researcher compared deidentified exam scores of the two groups.</p>
            <p>Which of the following is the reason this experiment was <em style="bold">not</em> blind?</p>
        </body>
        <input labels="false" shuffle="true">
            <choice value="A">The sample sizes in both groups was large.</choice>
            <choice value="B">Researchers looked at exam scores for the two groups.</choice>
            <choice value="C">The students knew whether or not music was playing while they were
                taking the exam. </choice>
            <choice value="D">Some of the students may not have studied for the exam.</choice>
            <choice value="E">Students were randomized into the two groups.</choice>
        </input>
        <part>
            <response match="A" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Blinding in study design has nothing to do with the size of
                    the samples.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="B" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Since the researcher looked at scores without student names and
                    conditions after the exam was complete, she was &#x201C;blind&#x201D; to which students were in
                    each of the two conditions.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="C" score="10">
                <feedback>Correct. Blinding in study design is when the subjects don&#x27;t know which
                    treatment they&#x27;re getting. In this case, the treatments are background music or
                    no background music. The students would certainly be aware of whether music was
                    playing during the exam, so they would know which treatment they got.
                </feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="D" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Blinding in study design does not refer to whether the
                    students know the answers on the exam. It refers to whether the subjects are
                    aware of something else pertaining to the study.</feedback>
            </response>
            <response match="E" score="0">
                <feedback>Incorrect. Having two randomized groups isn&#x27;t what determines whether or
                    not a study is blind.</feedback>
            </response>
        </part>
    </multiple_choice>
</pool>
